LUCAS J. ECKMAN

(202)-642-6766 <u>lucas.eckman@gmail.com</u> <u>lucaseckman.com</u> <u>github.com/eckmLJE</u> <u>LinkedIn</u>

Full stack web developer with a lifelong passion for learning and problem solving. While managing complex real estate development and urban design projects in Washington, DC over the past four years, I have seen the striking potential for technology to address many of the hardest challenges in business and society. Building on an established record of team-building and project management, I am eager to apply my fresh experience in Javascript, React, and Ruby on Rails to take on exciting opportunities in software engineering.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript ES6, ReactJS (Redux, Router, Thunk), Ruby on Rails, HTML5 + CSS3
- SQL (SQLite + PostgreSQL), Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Git, RSpec, Mocha
- > SVG illustration + animation (svg.js), Unity VR with Google Cardboard

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

ConcertPlan - lucaseckman.com/concertplan - Github: Front End | Back End

Friend groups view upcoming concerts and tickets and make plans to go to concerts together

- Calls Ticketmaster Discovery API for up to the minute concert and ticket data.
- Implements user authorization with JWT and bcrypt.
- ReactJS Front End, Ruby on Rails Back End. Pure CSS with no UI framework. Also uses Redux, ConnectedRouter, Moment, and Thunk.

RoomSeek - <u>lucaseckman.com/roomseek</u> - Github: <u>Front End</u>

Single-page application that allows users to find an available bedroom in an apartment by setting price and date filters

- > React & Redux in a clean and simple interface with few dependencies
- > SVG elements render interactive, dynamic floor plans
- > Floor plans are generated programmatically from database attributes of rooms and furniture (length, width, shape, etc.)

Parsel - Blog Post - Github: Front End | Back End

Highlight, parse and comment on political speech by highlighting text on the page linked to annotations

- > Built in three phases: first in vanilla JS, then introducing React, and finally Redux with Thunk and Connected Router.
- ReactJS Front End, Ruby on Rails Back End, Semantic UI React CSS Framework

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Real Estate Development Consultant

March 2015 - March 2018 | Washington, DC

Clients: Ditto Residential, Brook Rose Development, D.B. Lee Development & Construction

- Achieved 100% occupancy in initial lease-up of two rental properties in Northeast DC, including cutting-edge co-living product, OSLO.

 Worked directly with CEO and Marketing VP to troubleshoot leasing strategy and processes.
- > Shepherded sprawling Union Market warehouse redevelopment project from pre-acquisition to unanimous DC Zoning Commission approval. Developed project prospectus and presented to international hotel brands and operators. Collaborated with DC non-profit organization CulturalDC to design subsidized arts program to serve as signature cultural attraction within hotel.
- > Direct oversight and management of internal construction teams as well as external partners, e.g. architects, market data consultants, environmental consultants, community organizations and political officials.

Collective Group LLC

September 2013 - March 2015 | Washington, DC

Operations Director

- > Bootstrapped operations processes for 300-member social impact film conference held during Sundance Film Festival with minimal staff. Event featured documentary film panel discussions, gourmet dinners, live musical performances, and market activations for major sponsors on Main Street in Park City.
- > Hired and managed core team of music director, event designer, security chief, and A/V production. Trained and managed just-in-time group of 20+ volunteer event staff.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School - Completed August 2018. Full Stack Web Development Immersive Program: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and React.

Columbia University - New York, NY - 2007 to 2009

Kenyon College - Gambier, OH - 2004 to 2005